Thank you, New York.
It's humbling to be speaking to you
as Mayor.
[Sheila] Vanessa's resistance
is hurting you with traditional voters.
[Fisk] My wife and I, we have work to do.
[Buck] Dr. Glenn, allow me to introduce
Mayor and Mrs. Fisk.
Hector Ayala?
You know, they're saying you killed a cop?
[Hector] Look, I didn't push him, I swear.
[Matt] I'd still like to represent you.
Hector, he's not the man I married.
[Matt] White Tiger?
You neglect to tell me
- that you moonlight as a vigilante?
- Someone's gotta protect the streets.
I need you to find the witness
that Hector saved on the platform.
[knock on door]
[Matt] Nicky. You're the only person
standing between
Hector and consecutive life sentences.
Where is he?
Sadly, he's no longer here.
You don't want to do this.
[grunting]
[screaming]
[keys jingling]
- [buzzer sounds]
- [door unlocks]
[Matt] Thanks.
[creaking]
[lock clicking]
They, uh, bring you some food?
No.
[Hector breathes deeply]
Luquillo is a beach
near where I'm from in Puerto Rico.
To me,
it's the most beautiful place on Earth.
White sand, palm trees, and the coquis.
It's a little tree frog.
Doesn't croak. It sings its name.
[whistling coqui's call]
[laughs] I laugh
because the tourists, man,
they think it's noisy and annoying,
but to us boricuas,
man, it's a magical sound.
[♪ mellow music playing]
And the coqui, it mates for life, right?
So, every sunset...
thousands of these frogs start calling out
to their one and only love.
It's the music of the island.
You're gonna see that beach again, Hector.
I promise.
And you'll be reunited with your family.
[exhales sharply]
[♪ theme music playing]
[ship horn bellows]
[engine revving]
[passenger] Yo, what's up?
- Be cool. It's a gimme.
- [engine stops]
No one plays cowboy.
[exhales softly]
[sniffles] Evenin', gentlemen.
Whoo! Nippy, isn't it?
[Devlin chuckles]
I couldn't trouble you for the keys
to this fine vehicle, could I?
- Here you go.
- Thank you very much.
And, uh... wallets, while you're at it.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
You too, Susan.
Do you know whose truck this is?
Oh.
Are you a hard man, are ya?
Yeah.
Silly wee bastard.
[gun fires]
[gasps, chuckles]
[♪ upbeat music playing,
Salvi "Mi Canto"]
I look over my shoulder, but I grew up
in the city. I'm not afraid,
but somebody invades my privacy,
I have no problem taking my piece
and putting it to their head. That's it.
[man] Long, dark nights out here, man.
Good versus evil, evil versus evil,
good versus good.
Is New York gonna make it? I don't know.
You want answers from me?
I don't have 'em, sorry.
[♪ music continues muffled]
I hear Bacon's Freud triptych
is coming up for auction... again.
The yellow one.
You remember.
I remember.
I could wash two hundred million
through that sale.
I know that it hurts to just sit by,
but I'm reaching for higher goals.
Such as?
[knock on door]
[Sheila] Sorry to bother you, sir,
but you wanted to be updated on anything
happening near the Red Hook Port.
- [Fisk] Yes.
- [Sheila] Yeah.
Last night, there was a double homicide
not half a mile from the port.
Apparently, a hijacking gone wrong.
It really doesn't help
sell the place as a destination.
We should make the appropriate calls...
and inspire Chief Gallo
to make it a priority.
Yeah, we can try.
[footsteps recede]
[Vanessa] They're misbehaving because
there's no one at the head of the table.
Without you or me there,
they'll turn on each other.
They're rats.
Rats at the bottom of the barrel.
Let them kill each other.
[Vanessa] And when
they're done with each other,
whoever is left standing
will come after you.
That world, that kind of violence,
petty blood feuds...
None of it is our concern.
[footsteps approaching]
[chorus vocalizing]
[sighs]
[Powell, echoing] Yeah, okay.
I'll be right there.
[door opens]
You know, you don't need
those glasses indoors, right?
[sputters] I'm sorry,
are you talking to me?
Who's there?
[♪ uneasy music playing]
So, you're a blind lawyer who can fight.
Ah.
Officer Powell.
You know, Murdock, I bet Judge Cooper
would be interested to hear
that you're interfering
with a police investigation.
Oh, I think you mean a shakedown.
It doesn't exactly seem ethical.
I bet he'd throw you right off the case.
Well, at least I won't go to jail.
Witness tampering is a serious offense.
Now, maybe you get lucky, and the DA only
slaps you with a misdemeanor...
but I doubt it.
I'll see you in court, Officer.
[♪ heavy metal music playing
over speakers, Slayer "Crionics"]
I think you've misunderstood
the concept of a safe house.
Probably got eyes on us.
He says it relaxes him or whatever.
That's what this is for.
Hey! Cherry Cola,
you're back, man. Finally.
This is it? Come on, man.
First of all, it's not a party.
I'm not your man.
And this is just for me to get you
on the stand without sweating and puking.
Relax. I got you. Hey.
For how long have you been with the NYPD,
Officer Powell?
Uh, just over 15 years.
[Hochberg] And in those 15 years,
how many commendations of excellence
have you received?
[Powell] Three. I got one for integrity
and two for community service.
[Hochberg] Would you say it was unusual
for an officer of your seniority
to be working on New Year's Eve?
[Powell] Well, I volunteered.
Well, a lotta the guys in my precinct,
they got families, you know, kids,
and mine are grown. Kel's too.
Kel, Officer Shanahan, your partner?
Yeah. We were assigned
to Washington Heights,
and lotta the guys got sent down
to Times Square for the ball drop.
Did you and Officer Shanahan
see much action that night?
[Powell] We didn't see any action
until we got down
to the platform on 168th.
[Hochberg] Hm. What happened there?
[Powell] Well, we were just finishing up
a routine sweep.
You know, the place was like a ghost town,
and... uh, the defendant,
he just came outta nowhere.
He had this wild look in his eyes,
and when you're a cop long enough,
you know what that look means,
and he starts running toward us.
[inhales sharply]
[Hochberg, echoing] Did you tell
the defendant to stop?
[heartbeat thumping]
[Powell, echoing] Yes, many times.
[softly] Don't react, Hector.
[Powell] We yelled and flashed our badges,
but he just kept on coming.
He starts pounding on us, and then...
I feel Kel pull him off me.
Next thing I know, the guy just takes Kel
and pushes him in front of the train.
Like it was nothin'.
[Hochberg] Like it was nothing?
Objection. Leading.
- [Judge Cooper] Sustained.
- [Hochberg exhales]
[Hochberg] Officer Powell,
I know how hard this is for you.
Me and Kel Shanahan,
we were partners for eight years.
You know,
that's eight years of beers and kids,
and just talking about how shitty
the Knicks are.
[chuckles softly]
Kel Shanahan was my best friend.
And that's all over now.
[Hochberg] No further questions.
[♪ uneasy music playing]
Officer Powell, good morning, um...
I'm told you have a black eye.
- I hope everything is okay.
- Yeah, don't worry about it.
You know,
there's this thing they say in boxing.
The best cure for a black eye
is fast hands.
- Objection.
- [Judge Cooper] Sustained.
Come on, Mr. Murdock.
[Matt] Officer Powell, I just wanna
make sure I'm clear on something.
You testified that
before my client arrived at the station,
the place was a ghost town.
Yeah.
[Matt] Meaning you and your partner
were alone on the platform.
[Powell] Yes.
[Matt] Now,
language can be strange sometimes
so I just want to make sure
we're saying the same thing here.
By "alone," you mean
just the two of you, no one else?
- [Powell] That's right.
- There's no passenger waiting for a train?
No.
No busker playing a guitar?
- No.
- [Matt] Okay. So you're alone.
No buskers or passengers.
Which means there certainly wasn't
a confidential informant
- you were roughing up.
- Objection!
[Judge Cooper] You better have
a good faith basis for this, Mr. Murdock.
[Matt] Yeah, I do, Your Honor.
[Judge Cooper] Tight leash,
if you get my meaning.
Officer Powell, let's try this.
You ever met a man named Nicky Torres?
I never heard of him.
That's curious, 'cause as I understand it,
Nicky Torres is a confidential informant
who used to work with the NYPD.
In fact, he used to work with you
and Officer Shanahan directly.
Officer Powell,
did you and Officer Shanahan
have an arranged meeting with Nicky Torres
on the platform that night?
I told you, I don't know him.
Yeah. You did say that.
Thank you.
[echoes] Torres cannot testify.
[Forrest] He's almost ready.
- What's he doin'?
- Should I be worried?
[Cherry] Yep.
Hey, you promised I'd be safe.
You'll be fine if you stay out of sight.
Come on, let's go.
[♪ tense music playing]
Looking at the doors
isn't gonna get them here any faster.
Who says I'm looking at the doors?
They'll be here.
[engine revving]
[court officer] All rise.
Supreme Court State of New York,
part 20 is in session.
The Honorable Fitzgerald Cooper presiding.
[handcuffs clinking]
[sighs]
- You good?
- Yeah.
[tires screeching]
[siren blaring]
Mr. Murdock, call your witness.
Just another second, Your Honor.
Mornin', Officer.
Get outta the van, asshole.
[softly] Where is he?
Open it.
- [Forrest] You good?
- Yeah.
[Forrest] Come on! Let's go!
[door opens]
- They're here.
- [Matt sighs]
Impeccable timing, buddy.
Would you state your name for the record?
Yeah. My name's Nicky Torres.
[Matt] And, uh, where do you live,
Mr. Torres?
[Torres] Washington Heights.
So, are you close
to the 168th Street subway station?
[Torres] Yeah,
it's four blocks from my house.
[Matt] Where're you working right now?
I'm between jobs at the moment.
Right, you've had a rough
couple of years, huh?
[Torres] Eighteen months ago,
I got pinched for dealing.
I knew I shouldn't have done it,
but I got a kid. I needed money.
[Matt] So, you were looking
at a prison sentence.
What happened with that case?
It went away.
[Matt] Can you tell the jury why?
[Torres] I told the cops
I'd help 'em out sometimes.
[Matt] And by "help out," you mean
become a confidential informant?
Yeah.
Mr. Torres, is that what you were doing
on the night of New Year's Eve?
Were you passing along information
to Officers Shanahan and Powell?
[♪ tense music playing]
[heart thumping]
Remembering you're under oath.
No. I was home all night.
[Matt] Forgive me, I'm confused here.
Previously, you stated pretty clearly that
you were actually at the 168th Street
subway station being beaten
- when Hector Ayala saved your life.
- Objection.
- Objection!
- [Judge Cooper] Sustained.
He put himself in harm's way, didn't he?
- [Kirsten] Matt! Matt!
- [Judge Cooper] Counsel, stand down!
[scattered murmuring]
[exhales sharply] Well, this is bullshit.
- [softly] Just end it.
- Well, what's it gonna be, Mr. Murdock?
I withdraw the witness, Your Honor.
[Judge Cooper]
Mr. Torres, you are dismissed.
[scattered murmuring]
[♪ tense music continues]
The mayor's 30 minutes late.
He won't be joining us.
Now, the shootout two days ago at the port
is just the latest in a long line
of very noisy mistakes.
Truck hijackings, violence at the docks,
a gang war...
These are the headlines splashed across
the front page of The Examiner.
It all ends today.
We don't take orders from you, son.
That's not how things work.
Luca.
This is what you owe Viktor.
Restitution.
1.8. I like the sound of that.
Are you out of your mind?
Maybe next time, hire guys
who know how to jack a truck!
Maybe you shouldn't have hired
a bunch of trigger-happy assholes.
Enough! You're proving my point.
All this arguing, bloodshed, chaos...
It's getting in the way.
1.8. That's the number.
Oh, yeah? I got a better idea.
How about I pay zero dollars to Viktor,
and you go tell Fisk
if he's got something to say to me,
he can come tell me himself?
I don't take orders
from the mayor's errand boy!
I don't work for the mayor.
I work for the man.
[Kirsten] So he was fine
when we prepped him.
He's an annoying pain in the ass,
but he was fine.
So what the hell happened?
Maybe the cops got to him,
or they threatened his kid.
Or he was never on our side
in the first place.
[Cherry] So what do we have without Nicky?
[Matt] Nothing. Our entire defense
just got flushed down the toilet.
[sighs deeply]
[Kirsten] Maybe there's a paper trail,
some kind of CI registration form
or a record of payments or something?
We get that, we can recall him
as a hostile witness.
I looked. There's nothin'.
Powell did everything cash,
kept it all off the books.
He testify for them?
- Is there a case we can hang on him?
- [Cherry] Nothing I found.
He's innocent. We put him on the stand.
He tells his side of the story. The truth.
And we hope the jury see him
the way we do.
It's our only move.
We're gonna need a lot more bourbon.
[bottle opens]
[Fisk] What you're trying to do,
it's not going to work.
Counseling?
Tell me.
[clicks tongue]
I sent Buck to Luca
to tell him to pay Viktor
1.8 restitution for the hijacking.
Let's not fall into a place
where I don't trust you.
[Vanessa sighs]
I don't like watching
everything fall apart.
I respect that.
You wanted to keep the peace.
Sometimes, peace needs to be broken,
and chaos must reign,
just for a moment,
to build a stronger order.
Is that what it is?
Chaos before a stronger peace?
Or is it my penance? For what I did.
- No.
- You're punishing me for Adam.
- I'm not punishing you for anything!
- You're leaving me out in the cold.
Thank you for your patience.
Now, where were we?
[♪ dramatic music playing]
Mr. Ayala, how often would you say
you're at the 168th Street subway station?
A few times a week.
It's close to the apartment.
[Matt] Were you there on New Year's Eve?
Yes.
[Matt] Would you mind walking us through
what happened that night?
[Hector] Yeah, I bought
some flowers at la bodega,
and I was heading down to the station.
[Matt] Where were you going, Mr. Ayala?
[Hector sniffles]
[Matt] Mr. Ayala?
My wife and I,
we, uh, live with my sister and my niece.
Soledad and I, we've always dreamt
of having our own place,
and I had finally saved up the money.
I put a deposit down on a studio
in the South Bronx.
It's not much, but it's ours.
I was going there
to put the flowers there for the next day.
'Cause you wanted to surprise your wife.
- Yes.
- [Matt chuckles softly]
[Matt] Okay, so,
you were heading into the station.
What happens next?
[Hector] I heard yelling.
Sounded like someone
was in trouble, so I ran down...
to see what was going on.
[Matt] What did you see?
[Hector] A man getting beat up.
Did you know the man?
No. And I never saw him again
until yesterday in court.
And now I know his name is Nicky Torres.
[scattered murmuring]
[Matt] What about the men
who were doing the beating?
- Did you know them?
- [Hector] No.
[Matt] Did you know
they were police officers?
No. No, I yelled at them to stop
and they didn't.
So I ran down to help.
And then,
everything just happened so fast.
I tried to break it up,
then they started beating on me,
and I tried to fight them off
and then, all of a sudden, one of them
slipped and fell onto the tracks.
I was just trying to help.
I didn't want anyone to get hurt.
[Matt] Could've just walked away.
Ignored the problem.
You decided to risk your own safety
to help a stranger.
Wasn't the first time, was it?
- Uh, I don't understand.
- [Matt] Well, I'm just saying
that you've put yourself
in harm's way before. Many times.
The question is why?
Because he was in trouble.
[Matt] You intervened that night
'cause you're a hero.
Matt, don't do this.
Matt, don't do it.
Mr. Ayala, yes or no. Are you
the vigilante known as the White Tiger?
- Objection, Your Honor!
- Order!
- Yes or no? Mr. Ayala?
- [Judge Cooper] Order!
[gavel banging]
Order in my court!
[chorus vocalizing]
Both of you, in my Chambers, now.
Boy, you are a real slippery
piece of shit, you know that?
You sat in that very spot,
and you misled me.
You made representations to me,
you conned me
into suppressing this information,
you lectured me
about what's right and wrong,
and then, you have the nerve to stand up
and make a mockery of my courtroom?
That wasn't my intention, Your Honor.
They somehow got to my star witness.
My hand was forced.
What happened to all that lofty rhetoric
about "unfairly biasing the jury?"
[Matt] Hector's alter ego
is critical to this case.
What he's done as the White Tiger
speaks to the strength of his character.
- My God.
- It's well within my rights--
Is there a Division of Hypocrisy
at Murdock and Associates?
All right, stop it, both of you! Stop it.
[sighs] I can strike this from the record,
but that is pointless.
I can declare a mistrial,
but it's out already,
so I'd say that ship has sailed.
Put me in quite a bind, Mr. Murdock.
I didn't mean to disrespect the court,
Your Honor.
Let me be clear.
You blew open this door, Mr. Murdock.
Which means--
Yeah. It's open season on my client.
I get it.
Well, that's it.
Thank you, Your Honor.
[Hochberg sniffles, clears throat] Um...
Just... I sit atop a pyramid
- of over 500 ADAs.
- Mm.
You're not gonna be able
to stumble into traffic court
without one of them up your ass.
I hope it was worth it.
[man] I don't think that
Mr. Ayala is gonna get a fair trial.
You know why? He's Puerto Rican.
He's gonna single him out.
If you have enough evidence,
he should go to prison,
but give him a fair trial,
which I don't think he's gonna get it.
[♪ tense music playing]
You should've asked me first.
[Matt] I know.
It wasn't your secret to tell.
Just trying to keep you
outta prison, buddy.
We were losing,
and I had to take a big swing.
You know, Hector, if you are acquitted,
your White Tiger days are over.
I mean, you know that, right?
You can't... ever put that suit back on.
[♪ pensive music playing]
I don't think you understand.
Being the White Tiger
is more than just putting on a suit.
It's who I am.
[chuckles softly]
It's a calling.
I didn't choose it. It chose me.
Might as well ask me to stop breathing.
[Matt chuckles softly]
There are other ways to help.
Other ways to contribute.
Ways that don't require a mask.
You have to think about your family now.
They need you.
And for what it's worth,
I think you might be surprised
at how much you don't miss being him.
[Michael] We had just dropped
our son off at a game.
We were driving home,
and this SUV, it runs a stop sign,
and it just plows right into us.
The engine caught on fire.
[voice breaking] I tried to open the door,
but it was stuck.
I thought for sure we were dead.
Until all of a sudden,
I see someone running toward us.
It was White Tiger.
He saved our lives.
[Gianna] A few weeks ago,
I was leaving work.
It was late, and I have to cut through
this alley to get home.
And this guy, he tries to grab me.
I screamed,
but then I saw he had a knife.
I was so scared.
If White Tiger hadn't been there,
I don't know what would've happened.
[Kirsten] And now, let's hear
from a more objective party.
This is a police report
filed by Officer Lucas Barlow.
"On the night of October 2nd,
at 2:38 a.m.,
"I responded
to an attempted burglary call.
"When I arrived,
the suspect was hiding in an alley,
"and before I could draw my weapon,
he attacked me without provocation.
"We fought.
And then, White Tiger appeared.
"He intervened, pulled the suspect off me,
"then helped me
subdue and arrest the suspect."
[Matt] More police reports.
Officer Reyes, Officer Wong,
Officer Morales, Officer Grant...
All of these tell a different version
of the same story,
and it isn't the story of a man
who has a vendetta against the police.
In fact, I think many of the people
in this room
would consider White Tiger to be an ally.
Mr. Ayala,
let's talk about Mr. and Mrs. Burgos.
Why would you risk your life by running
toward a burning car to save strangers?
It's the right thing to do.
[Matt] What about Gianna Moreno?
You again put yourself in harm's way. Why?
It's the right thing to do.
[Matt] And when you saw
Officer Barlow was in trouble,
you ran in
when others would've run out. Why?
[echoing] It's the right thing to do.
[Matt] The police said
that Hector attacked them,
that he came outta nowhere.
That's what they said.
But why would Hector, the White Tiger...
Why would he do this without the amulet
that gives him
extraordinary strength and power?
Would any of you walk into battle
with one arm tied behind your back?
I wouldn't.
Every night, Hector Ayala
goes out and risks his life
to keep his neighborhood safe,
to protect his community.
So ask yourselves,
does this sound like the type of man
who'd murder a police officer
in cold blood?
He is a man of integrity.
The community says so.
[chuckles] The police say so.
The mask doesn't make the man.
And whether Hector Ayala's wearing
a White Tiger suit or not,
he's a hero.
Thank you.
[Hochberg] You know, every morning,
I get up, I kiss my wife, I call my kids,
I go to work to serve the people
of this great city,
I go to church every Sunday,
I sit in my usual pew,
I give money to my parish,
then I drive out to Queens
to see my mother.
Does that make me a good person?
That was a trick question.
You see, frankly, it's a false premise.
Good people can do bad things.
Bad people can do good things.
Humans... [scoffs] All of us.
We're messy, complicated,
capable of good, capable of evil.
Yes, Hector Ayala
might have done some good things.
Does that make him incapable
of doing a bad thing?
Of course not.
Do you know what happens to a person
when they get hit by a train?
When you have
200,000 pounds of steel slam into you,
all of your bones break,
all of your organs are eviscerated,
your body twists up
like a circus balloon full of blood.
But here's the kicker, you're still alive.
You don't actually die
until they back the train up,
and then your body, it just bursts.
And that is exactly what happened
to Officer Shanahan
when Hector Ayala pushed him
in front of that train.
But we're supposed to be okay
with that, right?
Because he's done
some nice things for people.
Because "it was the right thing to do."
Look around you.
These men and woman you see sitting here,
they're officers of the law.
They took an oath to protect
even in the face of danger.
And every single day,
these brave men and women show up
to serve the people of this city,
to serve you, to serve me,
and they do all that without a mask.
If Hector's sole intent was to do good
for his community, why is he hiding?
Because the last time I checked,
real heroes don't need to hide.
[chorus vocalizing]
[hushed chatter]
Hey.
- [Kirsten] You okay?
- [handcuffs clinking]
Has the jury reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
Will the defendant please rise?
In the matter of
the People v. Hector Ayala,
on the count of murder
in the first degree,
the jury finds the defendant...
- not guilty.
- [scattered gasps]
On the count of murder
in the second degree,
the jury finds the defendant not guilty.
On the count of manslaughter
in the first degree,
the jury finds the defendant not guilty.
[indistinct chatter]
[Judge Cooper] This matter is concluded.
[chorus vocalizing]
[Matt] Congratulations, buddy.
[Judge Cooper] Mr. Ayala,
you're free to go.
Thank you, Your Honor. Thank you.
[exclaims]
- [softly] Thanks.
- [Matt] Congratulations, Hector.
- [cameras clicking]
- [Matt] Thank you, all. Thank you.
[reporter] Mr. Murdock,
how do you respond to Mayor Fisk
calling you
and all vigilantes cop killers?
We're grateful
that justice was served, everyone.
There's no further comment at this stage.
Thank you.
[♪ uneasy music playing]
Daniel.
Yes, sir.
Your friend, the journalist, BB...
All due respect, sir,
we have people at the Times.
Tell her I wanna see her again.
Absolutely.
[Heather] Gotta love a man who cooks.
And dinner for one in public
is a bit depressing.
[chuckles] Tell me about it.
So, is this the Matt Murdock victory lap?
You win the Ayala case,
and now you get to enjoy the spoils?
Not quite yet. One thing's missing.
You see, my old partner and I,
straight out of law school,
we were so broke,
we pooled about everything we had together
for an office bottle of O'Melveny's.
- [Heather chuckles]
- Only broke it open when we won.
Needless to say, the first bottle lasted
a very long time.
[both chuckle]
Just a nice little reminder that...
once in a while, the system works.
You're talking about your friend,
Foggy Nelson, right?
Yeah.
I was kinda wondering when you would.
It's not easy.
He certainly knew how to enjoy
the good moments when they came.
Well then,
here's to a man who cooks,
a well-won case,
and Foggy Nelson.
May God hold them all
in the hollow of his hand.
[glasses clink]
[Fisk] The Ayala verdict
is an absolute miscarriage of justice.
Well, sir, a court and a jury
found him not guilty.
Courts fail. Juries get it wrong.
I should know.
And now, a masked vigilante,
a murderer,
is allowed to roam the streets,
and a veteran of the NYPD lies dead.
["Una Palabra" by Carlos Valera playing]
[Fisk] These vigilantes are a threat
to any society
that's based on the rule of law.
A man who wears a mask
to cover his face...
is a coward.
These vigilantes, they are not heroes.
[woman screams]
And I ran on a promise,
and the acquittal of Hector Ayala
demands that I keep it.
- [gun fires]
- [bullet casing clatters]
The rule of law must prevail.
[coqui whistling]
[water sloshing]
[waves lapping]
[♪ melancholy music playing]